Guide to the Records of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission 1905-1913 (Bulk 1909-1911) MS 314
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Financial Documents
  - Subseries II.C. Committee Financial Documents
    - Naval Parade Committee, 1909 Sept. 16-1909 Dec. 20 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
    - Richmond Borough Committee, 1909 Oct. 9 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
    - Ways and Means Committee, 1909 Jul. 28-1909 Aug. 25 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
    - Cashbook: Committees, 1909 Jul. 26-1910 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 26)
    - Ledger: Committees, 1909 Sept.-1910 Feb (Offsite-box 40, Volume 27)
  - Subseries II.D. Payment Vouchers
    The vouchers in this subseries document the financial transactions between the Commission and other individuals and companies. The funding source for the various vouchers is noted by the folder title. In addition, this subseries contains schedules for the various vouchers, which act as indexes for the series. The documents are arranged by voucher number.
    - Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, Schedule, 1906 Apr. 28-1908 Jun. 10 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, 1-75, 1906 Oct. 2-1908 May 1 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, 75-130, 1908 May 12-1909 Feb. 9 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, A11, A12, 1908 Jan. 2-1908 May 11 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, Schedule, 1909 Feb. 10-1909 Sept. 8 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 1-50, 1909 Jan. 9-1909 Mar. 12 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 51-100, 1909 Mar. 6-1909 Apr. 13 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 101-150, 1909 Apr. 6-1909 May 28 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 151-200, 1909 May 8-1909 Jun. 16 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 201-250, 1909 Jun. 5-1909 Jun. 19 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 251-300, 1909 Jun. 12-1909 Aug. 27 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 301-350, 1909 Jun. 23-1909 Aug. 30 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 351-400, 1909 Aug. 17-1909 Aug. 26 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 401-429, 1909 Jul. 31-1909 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 1-50, 1909 Sept. 14-1909 Nov. 29 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 51-100, 1909 Aug. 28-1909 Nov. 5 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 101-150, 1909 Sept. 11-1909 Nov. 20 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 151-200, 1909 Oct. 8-1909 Nov. 27 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 201-259, 1909 Sept. 30-1909 Nov. 22 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 399-968, 1909 Oct. 30-1909 Dec. 10 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, Schedule, 1910 Jan. 14-1910 Jan. 27 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 1-300, 1909 Aug. 14-1909 Nov. 17 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 300-350, 1909 Oct. 15-1909 Nov. 3 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 351-398, 1909 Oct. 15-1909 Nov. 30 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 422-400, 1909 Sept. 17-1909 Nov. 20 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 451-525, 1909 Nov. 12-1909 Dec. 3 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 526-600, 1909 Oct. 8-1909 Dec. 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 601-650, 1909 Oct. 2-1909 Dec. 11 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 651-700, 1909 Oct. 7-1909 Dec. 4 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 701-750, 1909 Sept. 29-1909 Dec. 3 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 751-800, 1909 Sept. 20-1909 Nov. 12 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 801-850, 1909 Sept. 25-1909 Dec. 14 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 851-900, 1909 Oct. 8-1909 Dec. 7 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 900-975, 1909 Sept. 28-1910 Jan. 8 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, Unnumbered (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 513 of the Laws of 1910, Schedule, 1910 Jul. 6 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 811 of the Laws of 1911, 1-2, 1911 Dec. 7 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5)
    - City Fund, 1-100, 1909 Jun. 23-1909 Oct. 13 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 6)
    - City Fund, 101-160, 1909 Oct. 13-1909 Dec. (Offsite-box 23, Folder 7)
    - City Fund, Unnumbered, 1909 Oct. (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
    - Open Market Order, Schedule, 1911 Jan. 27-1911 Mar. 21 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 9)
    - Open Market Order, 1-15, 1911 Jan. 27-1911 Apr. 27 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 2-25, 1909 Oct. 4-1909 Oct. 5 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 11)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 26-50, 1909 Oct. 1-1909 Oct. 20 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 12)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 51-65, 1909 Oct. 20 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 66-80, 1909 Oct. 20-1909 Oct. 23 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 81-100, 1909 Oct. 20 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 3)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 101-115, 1909 Oct. 20-1909 Oct. 22 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 4)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 116-145, 1909 Oct. 29 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 5)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 146-214, 1909 Oct. 27 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 6)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 216-240, 1909 Oct. 27-1909 Nov. 9 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 7)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 241-270, 1909 Nov. 5-1909 Nov. 29 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 271-290, 1909 Oct. 29-1909 Nov. 29 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 291-315, 1909 Nov. 13-1909 Nov. 22 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 316-348, 1909 Nov. 13-1910 Feb. 12 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 4)
    - Subscription Fund, 13-40, 1909 Mar. 22-1909 Aug. 10 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5)
    - Subscription Fund, 41-80, 1909 Aug. 6-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 6)
    - Subscription Fund, 81-120, 1909 Sept. 15-1909 Nov. 19 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 7)
    - Subscription Fund, 121-160, 1909 Sept. 29-1909 Nov. 19 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1)
    - Subscription Fund, 161-200, 1909 Oct. 25-1909 Dec. 2 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 2)
    - Subscription Fund, 201-230, 1909 Nov. 4-1909 Dec. 8 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 3)
    - Subscription Fund, 231-250, 1909 Nov. 30-1909 Dec. 8 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
    - Subscription Fund, 251-270, 1909 Nov. 27-1909 Dec. 23 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
    - Subscription Fund, 272-300, 1909 Nov. 27-1909 Dec. 15 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6)
    - Subscription Fund, 301-320, 1909 Dec. 3-1909 Dec. 22 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
    - Subscription Fund, 322-340, 1909 Dec. 4-1910 Jan. 4 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2)
    - Subscription Fund, 341-370, 1909 Dec. 7-1909 Dec. 25 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 3)
    - Subscription Fund, 371-400, 1909 Dec. 13-1910 Jan. 3 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 4)
    - Subscription Fund, 401-430, 1909 Dec. 31-1910 Jan. 25 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 5)
    - Subscription Fund, 431-460, 1910 Jan. 22-1910 Mar. 8 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 6)
    - Subscription Fund, 461-500, 1910 Mar. 1-1910 Jul. 28 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1)
    - Subscription Fund, 502-530, 1910 Apr. 15-1910 Jun. 25 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 2)
    - Subscription Fund, 531-570, 1910 Jul. 20-1910 Oct. 28 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 3)
    - Subscription Fund, 571-610, 1910 Oct. 27-1912 Jul. 1 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 4)
    - Subscription Fund, A1-A40, 1909 Nov. 8-1909 Nov. 29 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 5)
    - Subscription Fund, A41-A70, 1909 Nov. 10-1909 Nov. 29 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 6)
    - Subscription Fund, A71-A100, 1909 Nov. 11-1909 Dec. 1 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 1)
    - Subscription Fund, A101-A130, 1909 Nov. 11-1909 Nov. 26 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 2)
    - Subscription Fund, A131-A150, 1909 Oct. 11-1910 Jan. 27 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 3)
    - Subscription Fund, A151-A190, 1909 Nov. 29-1909 Dec. 30 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 4)
    - Subscription Fund, A191-A220, 1909 Nov. 23-1909 Dec. 13 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 5)
    - Subscription Fund, A221-A258, 1909 Nov. 27-1910 Feb. 3 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 6)
    - Subscription Fund, Unnumbered, 1909 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 7)
- Series III: Legal Documents
  - Subseries III.A.
    The legal documents in this collection consist of materials related to complaints against the Commission, as well as paperwork related to copyrighted materials (i.e. Celebration emblem, etc).
    - Certified copies of state laws, 1909 May 3-1909 June 3 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1)
    - Copyright, 1909 Mar. 6-1909 Sept. 11 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 2)
    - Erie Railroad Company, 1909-1911 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 3)
    - Pain Manufacturing Company, 1909-1910 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 4)
    - I.M. Southern & Company, 1909 Sept. 17-1909 Nov. 30 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 5)
    - Legal Documents, 1909-1910 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 6)
  - Subseries III.B. Contracts
    This subseries contains contracts and agreements between the Commission and various other parties, such as bands, architects, and vendors. In some instances, relevant correspondence and documents are filed with the contracts. The contracts are arranged alphabetically by the name of the second party.
    - Band Contracts: Bronx Parade, 1909 Sept. 25-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 7)
    - Band Contracts: Carnival Parade (Brooklyn), 1909 Sept. 27-1909 Oct. 7 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 8)
    - Band Contracts: Carnival Parade (Manhattan), 1909 Sept. 10-1909 Sept. 21 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 9)
    - Band Contracts: Historical Parade (Brooklyn), 1909 Sept. 21 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 10)
    - Band Contracts: Historical Parade (Manhattan), 1909 Sept. 8-1909 Sept. 25 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 11)
    - Band Contracts: Staten Island Parade, 1909 Sept. 24 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 12)
    - Contracts: A-Cam, 1909 Mar. 29-1909 Sept. 24 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    - Contracts: Car-Curtiss, 1909 Jun. 8-1909 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - Contracts: E-Med, 1909 Jul.-1909 Sept. 29 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
    - Contracts: Met-P, 1908 Mar. 30-1909 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 4)
    - Contracts: R-S, 1909 Feb. 8-1909 Oct. 14 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
    - Contracts: T-W, 1909 May 18-1909 Sept. 22 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Organizational Materials
  This series consists of materials related to the operation of the Commission, such as meeting minutes and stated procedures, as well as logistical materials related to the Celebration.
  - Lists of Commission members, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1)
  - Organizational procedures, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Annual Meeting of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1912 May 18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Committee on Badges, Flag, and Poster, 1909 Oct. 13 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Committee on Public Safety, 1909 Oct. 13 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1910 Jun. 10-1910 Sept. 13 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Joint Committee on Half Moon and Clermont, 1909 Nov. 3-1910 Sept. 13 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Trustees' Meetings, 1909 Oct. 14-1909 Nov. 24 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Trustees' Meetings, 1909 Dec. 22-1911 May 17 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 9)
  - Reports on various meetings, 1909 Aug. 31-1909 Sept. 11 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 10)
  - Order of Business for Trustees' Meeting, 1910 May 4 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 11)
  - Address book, circa 1908-1911 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 28)
  - Minutes: Hudson Tercentenary Joint Committee, 1905 Feb. 15-1906 Apr. 16 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 29)
  - First and second Annual Report, Minutes: Executive Committee, Trustees' Meetings (assistant secretary's copy), 1905 Dec. 16-1909 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 30)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, Trustees' Meetings, Upper-Hudson Committee (president's copy), 1905 Dec. 16-1909 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 31)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, Trustees' Meetings, Upper-Hudson Committee assistant secretary's copy), 1909 Jan. 27-1909 Oct. 8 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 32)
  - Minutes: Executive Committee, Trustees' Meetings, Upper-Hudson Committee (secretary's copy), 1909 Jan. 27-1909 Oct. 8 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 33)
  - Official documents: Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, Chapter 217 of the Laws of 1908, By-laws, Member list, Minutes, 1906 Apr.-1909 Jan. 23 (Offsite-box 42, Volume 34)
  - Official documents (includes copies of letters, calendar of events, guest list, and meeting minutes), 1909 Sept. 14-1910 Aug. 23 (Offsite-box 42, Volume 35)
  - Official documents: Committee on Plan and Scope, 1905 Jul. 13-1906 Jan. (Offsite-box 42, Volume 36)
  - Scrapbook, 1905 Nov. 28-1909 Apr. 23 (Offsite-box 42, Volume 37)
  - Scrapbook, 1909 Apr. 9-1910 Jun. 17 (Offsite-box 42, Volume 38)
  - Blueprints, 1909 Jul. (Offsite-box 32, Folder 12)
  - Inventories, circa 1909-1911 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 13)
  - Lists of official guests, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 14)
  - Lists of reception guests, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 15)
  - Requests made to Commission, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 32, Folder 16)
  - Schedules, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 32, Folder 17)
  - Speeches, 1909 Sept. 27-1909 Dec. 30 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 18)
  - Mrs. Spencer Trask's Lyrics to "America" (sung by Glee Club), Undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 19)
  - Samuel Verplanck Hoffman file of records, 1908-1909 (Offsite-box 37)
    Scope and Contents
    File of documents found on the shelf, separated from the collection. Added to the collection and finding aid in December 2021 by archivist Larry Weimer.
- Series V: Ephemera
  The ephemera in this collection consists of invitations, programs, tickets, and various other printed materials.
  - Invitations, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1)
  - Printed materials, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 2)
  - Programs, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 3)
  - Tickets, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 4)
  - Public Health & Convenience Committee. Armbands and banners (rolled), circa 1909 (Offsite-box 36)
    4 banners (23x36 inches): Rest Station, Medical Station, Comfort Station, Information Bureau. 4 arm bands (4x9 inches): Information Bureau attendant, medical station, doctor, nurse. (Items found on shelf in manila envelope, apparently having been separated from the collection, in December 2021 and added to the collection/finding aid at that time by archivist Larry Weimer.) Textiles rolled and encapsulated by conservator Alan Balicki in December 2021.
- Series VI: Clippings
  This series contains magazine and newspaper clippings about the Celebration.
  - Magazine Articles, 1909 Sept. 25-1909 Oct. 9 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1909 Apr. 4-1911 May 11 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 6)
- Series VII: The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission
  This series contains various drafts for The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1909, many of which contain editing notes.
  - Draft, Intro-Chapter X, 1910 May 21-1910 Dec. 27 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 7)
  - Draft, Chapter XI-XXXVI, 1910 Jun. 30-1910 Jul. 27 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 8)
  - Draft, Chapter XXXVII-XL, 1910 Jul. 19-1910 Aug. 2 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 9)
  - Draft, Chapter LVI-LX, 1910 Jul. 17-1910 Aug. 2 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 10)
  - Illustrations, circa 1910 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 11)
  - Draft, Intro-Chapter XXII, circa 1910 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 1)
  - Draft, Chapter XXII-L, circa 1910 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 2)
  - Draft, Chapter LI-LXII, Appendix, circa 1910 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 1)
  - The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, volume 1, 1910 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 39)
  - The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, volume 2, 1910 (Offsite-box 41, Volume 40)
- Series VIII: Materials unrelated to the Hudson-Fulton Celebration
  This series consists of miscellaneous materials related to the collection, such as visiting cards collected at the various events, materials relating to Robert Fulton, obituaries of Commission members, and loose envelopes from the collection.
  - Visiting cards, Undated (Offsite-box 35, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten notes, Undated (Offsite-box 35, Folder 3)
  - List of members of the Board of Alderman, 1909-1911 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 4)
  - Materials relating to Robert Fulton, Undated (Offsite-box 35, Folder 5)
  - Materials relating to Robert Fulton, Undated (Offsite-box 35, Folder 6)
  - Obituaries, 1909 Dec. 16-1911 Jun. 29 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook: Clarence Lexow obituaries, 1910 Dec. 31-1911 Jan. 1 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 8)
  - Description of Lexow Family Coat of Arms, circa 1911 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 9)
  - The Journal-News - Articles honoring Clarence Lexow, 1948 Jun. 15 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript copy from "The Homestead of a Colonial Dame" by Alice Crary Sulcliffe, 1909 (Robert Fulton's great-granddaughter) (Offsite-box 35, Folder 11)
  - Schedule of New York baseball games (used as place holders), 1909 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 12)
  - Loose envelopes, Undated (Offsite-box 35, Folder 13)